[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "A 42  year old illiterate lady presented with tachycardia, increased sweating, palpitations, heat intolerance and weight loss despite an increased appetite. An error had been made by a pharmacy technician while dispensing her oral contraceptive pills a month earlier - she was given L-thyroxine instead. Which of the following is most correct about her condition?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Her serum TSH, T4 and T3 are low",
      "She suffers from thyrotoxicosis",
      "She suffers from iatrogenic or factitious hyperthyroidism",
      "Long term oral contraceptive use can explain her condition",
      "This is and adverse drug reaction"
    ],
    "answer": ["She suffers from iatrogenic or factitious hyperthyroidism"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "A 42 year old cancer patient presents in the Emergency Room semi-conscious and disoriented. His pulse and blood pressure are 140/80mmHg and 94 beats per minute respectively, and his body temperature is 37.5⁰C. He has no peripheral oedema. Serum electrolytes and urea reveal sodium to be 125mMol/L. A cranial computed tomography scan reveals cerebral oedema. In which organ is his primary tumour most likely to be?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Brain(Pituitary)",
      "Kidney",
      "Lung",
      "Adrenal gland",
      "Brain(meninges)"
    ],
    "answer": ["Brain(Pituitary)"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of these is the most important environmental factor for type 2 diabetes?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Unhealthy food",
      "Stress",
      "Sedentary lifestyle",
      "Visceral Obesity",
      "carbohydrate"
    ],
    "answer": ["Visceral Obesity"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The two metabolic defects in types 2 diabetes are",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Insulin resistance & β-cell dysfunction",
      "β-cell hyperfunction & hyperinsulinemia",
      "Insulin resistance & β-cell hyperfunction",
      "β-cell dysfunction & hyperinsulinemia",
      "Chronic hyperglycaemia & β-cell hyperfunction"
    ],
    "answer": ["Insulin resistance & β-cell dysfunction"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Amylin deposition is characteristic of one of these endocrinopathies:",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Type 1 diabetes",
      "Type 2 diabetes",
      "Cushing disease",
      "Phaeochromocytoma",
      "Addison disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["Type 2 diabetes"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of these is the hallmark of diabetic macrovasular disease?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Increased vascular permeability",
      "Diffuse endothelial injury",
      "Accelerated atherogenesis",
      "Hyaline arteriolosclerosis",
      "Hyperplastic arteriolosclerosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Accelerated atherogenesis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of these is the most common cause of death in diabetics?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Renal failure",
      "Infections",
      "Myocardial infarction",
      "Diabetic eye disease",
      "Diabetic neuropathy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Myocardial infarction"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of these complications of diabetes is not attributed to accelerated atherosclerosis?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Chronic renal failure",
      "Gangrene of lower extremities",
      "Ischaemic heart disease",
      "Diabetic cataract",
      "Stroke"
    ],
    "answer": ["Diabetic cataract"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of these is the fundamental lesion in diabetic retinopathy?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Increased intra-ocular pressure",
      "Neovascularization",
      "Hyaline arteriolosclerosis",
      "Hyperplastic arteriolosclerosis",
      "vasculitis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neovascularization"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of these is the most frequent pattern of neuropathy seen in diabetes?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Mononeuropathy",
      "Proximal sensorimotor neuropathy",
      "Autonomic neuropathy",
      "Distal symmetric polyneuropathy",
      "Cranial nerve palsies"
    ],
    "answer": ["Distal symmetric polyneuropathy"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which of these disorders is the most common cause of endogenous hyperthyroidism?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Hyperfunctioning multinodular goiter",
      "Graves' disease",
      "Thyroid adenoma",
      "Iodine-induced hyperthyroidism",
      "Granulomatous thyroiditis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Graves' disease"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which of these option is the triad of Graves' disease?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Pretibial myxoedema,hyperthyroidism and ophthalmopathy",
      "Hypothyroidism, pretibial myxedema and ophthalmopathy",
      "Goiter, hyperthyroidism and myxoedema",
      "Goiter, hypothyroidism and ophthalmopathy",
      "Ophthalmopathy, hyperthyroidism and autoimmunity"
    ],
    "answer": ["Pretibial myxoedema,hyperthyroidism and ophthalmopathy"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which of these is the most common histologic type of thyroid cancer?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Anaplastic carcinoma",
      "Follicular carcinoma",
      "Medullary carcinoma",
      "Papillary carcinoma",
      "Hurthle cell carcinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Papillary carcinoma"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which of these is the most common tumour of the thyroid?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Follicular carcinoma",
      "Follicular adenoma",
      "Hurthle cell adenoma",
      "Papillary carcinoma",
      "Medullary carcinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Follicular adenoma"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Which of these thyroid cancers presents commonly with cervical lymph node metastasis?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Follicular carcinoma",
      "Medullary carcinoma",
      "Hurthle cell carcinoma",
      "Papillary carcinoma",
      "Aplastic carcinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Papillary carcinoma"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which of these is the most common type of hyperfunctioning pituitary adenoma?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Gonadotroph adenoma",
      "Lactotroph adenoma",
      "somatotroph adenoma",
      "Thyrotroph adenoma",
      "Corticotroph adenoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Lactotroph adenoma"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Which of these syndromes will result from severe anoxic injury of the anterior pituitary?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Nelson syndrome",
      "Cushing syndrome",
      "Sheehan syndrome",
      "Syndrome of inappropriate ADH secretion(SIADH)",
      "Conn syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Sheehan syndrome"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "A 30 year old female presents with skin, soft tissue and visceral enlargement, menstrual disturbances, hypertension and a diabetic range plasma glucose upon administration of an oral glucose load. Which of the following is in excess?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": ["IGF", "GH", "ADH", "Insulin", "Prolactin"],
    "answer": ["GH"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "A 35 year old female presents to the clinic with features of Weight loss, increased appetite, increased sweating, tachycardia and palpitations. The most likely diagnosis is",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Hyperthyroidism",
      "Hypothyroidism",
      "Hyperparathyroidism",
      "Thyrotoxicosis",
      "Addison disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["Hyperthyroidism"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Cortisol is synthesized mainly in the",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Posterior hypophysis",
      "Adrenal medulla",
      "Zonal fasciculata of the adrenal cortex",
      "Zona reticularis of the adrenal cortex",
      "Zona glomerulosa of adrenal cortex"
    ],
    "answer": ["Zonal fasciculata of the adrenal cortex"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Polyuria, nocturia and hyposthenuria are typical features of the following renal diseases",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Acute tubular necrosis",
      "Diabetic nephropnthy",
      "Berger's disense",
      "Membranous nephropath",
      "Tubulointerstitial nephrltis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Tubulointerstitial nephrltis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "A 4 year old boy presented with frothy urine few weeks after an upper respiratory tract infection. Light microscopy of the renal biopsy showed no relevant pathological findings and Electron microscopy showed effacement of the foot processes. Immunofluorescence is likely to show",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Strong linear IgG stain on glomerular capillary wall(GCW)",
      "Dominant IgA stain in the mesangial area",
      "Starry sky pattern of stain",
      "Granular IgM stain in the glomerular capillary wall",
      "No glomerular immune stain/deposit"
    ],
    "answer": ["No glomerular immune stain/deposit"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "The following renal lesions are associated with interstitial foam cells",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Secondary FSGS",
      "Primary FSGS",
      "Dense deposit disease",
      "Fibronectin glomerulopathy",
      "Thin basement membrane disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["Primary FSGS"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "A 6 year old child presented with purpuric skin rash, hematuria and proteinuria. Light microscopy showed mesangioproliferative glomerulonephritis. Immunofluorescence revealed strong granular IgA and IgG staining in the GCW. EM revealed mesangial deposits. What is the most plausible diagnosis,",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Anti GBM glomerulonephritis",
      "Henoch-Schonlein purpura",
      "Minimal change disease",
      "Fabry's disease",
      "IgA Nephropathy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Henoch-Schonlein purpura"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Tubulorecticular inclusions are seen in the following renal diseases",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Renal Tuberculosis",
      "HIV Nephropathy",
      "IgA nephropathy",
      "Amyloidosis",
      "Light chain Nephropathy"
    ],
    "answer": ["HIV Nephropathy"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Papillary necrosis can be seen in which of the following renal conditions",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Benign nephrosclerosis",
      "Renal artery stenosis",
      "Obstructive uropathy",
      "Malignant nephrosclerosis",
      "Thrombotic microangiopathies"
    ],
    "answer": ["Benign nephrosclerosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "A 35 year old female with a chronic history of severe dysmenorrhea. One of her coping strategies was to be on analgesic cocktail, mostly mixtures of 2 or 3 and occasionally of a single type. She recently came down with a renal disease with complaints of nocturia, hypertension and polyuria. What is the limit of the drug dosage to a renal disease and over what period",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "≥ 2kg over 3years",
      "≥ 2kg over lyear",
      "≥ 4kg over 3years",
      "≥ 10kg over 6years",
      "≥ 4kg over 4years"
    ],
    "answer": ["≥ 2kg over 3years"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Morphology of the Kidneys in Analgesic Nephropathy",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Coarse granular shrunken kidneys",
      "Mesangial immune deposits on electron microscopy",
      "Dominant IgA and IgG stain on immunofluorescence stain",
      "Tubulitis with occasional interstitial granulomas",
      "Interstitial foam cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Coarse granular shrunken kidneys"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Nephropathy associated with NSAIDs include",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Minimal change disease",
      "Membranous nephropathy",
      "Acute kidney injury",
      "Acute interstitial nephritis",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "About lupus nephritis",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Renal biopsy is needed for diagnosis",
      "Effacement of foot processes is a common feature",
      "Electron dense deposits are only intramembranous",
      "Immunofluorescence is strongly positive for only IgM",
      "Mesangioproliferative GN is a possible picture on light microscopy"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Mesangioproliferative GN is a possible picture on light microscopy"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "A 40 year old man presented with anasarca, hematuria, proteinuria and oliguria. Light microscopy showed glomeruli with endocapillary and mesangial hypercellularity. EM revealed subendothelial deposits. Which of the following is true about this case",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Minimal change disease Is the most likely diagnosis",
      "It is a case of membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis",
      "The features are those of a typical Nephrotic syndrome",
      "The features are those of a typical Nephritic syndrome",
      "This is a case of Fabry's disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["It is a case of membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "About Membranoproliferative GN",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "It is also known as Lipoid Nephritis",
      "Morphology may be normal on light microscopy",
      "The type II is known as dense deposit disease",
      "Only the alternate complement pathway is activated in the type I",
      "Typical appearance on JMS is the presence of spikes"
    ],
    "answer": ["The type II is known as dense deposit disease"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "A 50 year old Engineer came down with left flank mass, weight loss and hematuria. Histology of a biopsy sample showed renal cell carcinoma. What is/are the risk factor(s)?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Cigarette smoking",
      "Alcohol",
      "Diabetes mellitus",
      "Amyloidosis",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cigarette smoking"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Morphological variants of Renal Cell Carcinoma include;",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Clear cell",
      "Transitional cell",
      "Ductal cell",
      "Hurthle cell",
      "Medullary"
    ],
    "answer": ["Clear cell"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Presence of interstitial forms cells with non-nephrotic range proteinuria is suggestive of",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Minimal change disease",
      "Thin basement membrane disease",
      "FSGS",
      "Alport syndrome",
      "Goodpasture syndrome"
    ],
    "answer": ["Alport syndrome"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "The clinical features of a typical Nephrotic syndrome include;",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Massive proteinuria",
      "Anuria",
      "Palpebral oedema",
      "Hypertension",
      "Nocturia"
    ],
    "answer": ["Massive proteinuria"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Typical features of Nephritic syndrome include",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Lipiduria",
      "Hyposthenuria",
      "Hyperlipidemia",
      "Haematuria",
      "Polyuria"
    ],
    "answer": ["Haematuria"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "About Polycystic kidney disease",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "It is the most common cause of chronic kidney disease",
      "There are three forms",
      "They all have autosomal dominant mode of inheritance",
      "They all have autosomal recessive mode of inheritance",
      "May present with hypertension"
    ],
    "answer": ["May present with hypertension"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "The major glasses of thrombotic microangiopathies(TMAs) are",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Hemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS)",
      "Antiphospholipid Antibody syndrome",
      "Toxemia of pregnancy",
      "Thrombotic thrombocytopenia purpura",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "The following immune on EM matches their Iomerular lesions correctly;",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Intramembranous deposit and FSGS",
      "Subepithelial humps and Lupus nephritis",
      "Mesangial deposit and Minimal change disease",
      "Subendothelial deposit and Membranoproliferative GN",
      "Subepithelial deposit and Antl-GBM glomerulonephritis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Subendothelial deposit and Membranoproliferative GN"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "Neurons react to injury through the following means",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Red neurons",
      "Accumulation Of Rosenthal fibers",
      "Corpora amylacca deposit",
      "Gliosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Red neurons"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Morphology of cerebral oedema",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Shrunken brain",
      "Flattened gyri",
      "Widened sulci",
      "Dilated ventricular cavities"
    ],
    "answer": ["Flattened gyri"],
    "explanation": "Flattened gyri and narrow sulci in cerebral oedema",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Which ofthe following statements are true",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Oligodendrocytes are microglia",
      "Astrocytes are responsible for tissue repair in the CNS",
      "The ventricular surfaces are lined by astrocytes",
      "Neuron Specific Enolase is a marker for glial cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neuron Specific Enolase is a marker for glial cells"],
    "explanation": "marker for glial cells NSe, Niphphysin and n",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Reaction of astrocytes to injury include",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Fibrosis",
      "Lipofuscin formation",
      "Cell swelling",
      "Psammoma body deposits"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cell swelling"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "The following intracellular are correctly matched",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Cytoplasmic complex lipids and Tay-Sachs disease",
      "Cowdry and Nieman Pick disease",
      "Negri bodies and Herpetic infections",
      "Lewy bodies and Alzheimer disease"
    ],
    "answer": ["Cytoplasmic complex lipids and Tay-Sachs disease"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Which of these is not a form of brain herniations",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Subfalcine",
      "Transtentorial",
      "Cingulate",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Forebrain anomalies include",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "The Arnold-Chiari malformations",
      "Ihe Dandy-walker malformations",
      "Spina bifida",
      "Polymicrogyria"
    ],
    "answer": ["Polymicrogyria"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "About hemorrhages in the CNS",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Epidural hematoma is due to rupture of bridging veins",
      "Subdural hematoma is often due to rupture of middle meningeal artery",
      "Subdural hematoma is often due to rupture of bridging veins",
      "Subdural hematoma is uncommon in the elderly"
    ],
    "answer": ["Subdural hematoma is often due to rupture of bridging veins"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "More about heamorrhages in the CNS",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Subgaleal hematoma occurs just above the scalp aponeurosis",
      "Subarachnoid hemorrhage is most commonly due to systemic hypertension",
      "Subarachnoid hemorrhage is most commonly due to rupture of berry aneurysms",
      "Intraparenchymal hemorrhage may be a feature of concussion"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Subarachnoid hemorrhage is most commonly due to rupture of berry aneurysms"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Which of thee is not a component of hypertensive cerebrovascular disease",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Lacunar infarct",
      "Slit hemorrhages",
      "Hypertensive encephalopathy",
      "Hyaline arteriolosclerosis",
      "Formation of Saccular (berry) aneurysm"
    ],
    "answer": ["Formation of Saccular (berry) aneurysm"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "The following are sequelae of CNS infections except",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Dementia pugilistica",
      "Epilepsy",
      "Hearing loss",
      "Paralysis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Dementia pugilistica"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "HIV neuropathy includes the following except",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Meningoencephalitis",
      "Vacuolar myelopathy",
      "Peripheral neuropathy",
      "Neuritic plaque deposits"
    ],
    "answer": ["Neuritic plaque deposits"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "Alzheimer's disease",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Impairs higher intellectual function with alterations in mood and behavior",
      "Typically symptomatic before 50 years, incidence rises with age",
      "Most cases are familial",
      "Pathologic examination of brain tissue is optional for definitive diagnosis"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Impairs higher intellectual function with alterations in mood and behavior"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": " Concerning CNS tumors",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Intra-spinal tumors are most common than intracranial tumors",
      "Most childhood tumors arise in the posterior fossa",
      "Most adult tumors arise in the posterior fossa",
      "Most childhood tumors are supratentorial"
    ],
    "answer": ["Most childhood tumors arise in the posterior fossa"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "WHO grading of CNS tumors",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Most meningioma are WHO grade I/IV",
      "Papillary and Rhabdoid Meningioma are WHO grade II/IV",
      "Pilocytic Astrocytoma is WHO grade II/IV",
      "Embryonal tumors e.g. Medulloblastomas are WHO grade II/IV"
    ],
    "answer": ["Most meningioma are WHO grade I/IV"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "CNS tumors are different from tumors of other organs because",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "There is a clear distinction between benign and malignant lesions.",
      "Tumors at certain sites can fatal of the tumor type",
      "Surgical resection without compromise of neurologic function is easily done.",
      "They metastasize quickly"
    ],
    "answer": ["Tumors at certain sites can fatal of the tumor type"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Global cerebral ischemia",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Is reduction in blood flow to a part of the brain due to vessel occlusion",
      "Clinical outcome is the same irrespective of severity Of insult",
      "Glial cells are most vulnerable",
      "Gives rise to watershed infarct"
    ],
    "answer": ["Gives rise to watershed infarct"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "A 30 year old male died within 24 hours of arrival at the emergency unit with a presumed diagnosis of bacterial meningitis. At autopsy he had extensive purulent exudates at the base of the brain. What are the likely causative pathogens?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Streptococcus pneumoniae",
      "Staphylococcus aureus",
      "Neisseria meningitides",
      "Haemophilus influenza"
    ],
    "answer": ["Haemophilus influenza"],
    "explanation": "In adolescents and young adults, Nisseria meningitides is the commonest agent followed by Haemophilus influenzae. Patients present with signs of meningeal irritation such as headache, photophobia, irritability, neck stiffness and altered consciousness.Mortality can be reduced by effective Antibiotic agents. Untreated cases may be fatal.",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "The following CNS disorders are caused by protein misfolding",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Parkinson's disease",
      "Berry aneurysm",
      "Amyloid angiopathy",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "Concerning hydrocephalus:",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Always results in head enlargement",
      "There is compensatory enlargement of the ventricles in response to loss of brain tissue In hydrocephalus ex vacuo",
      "Stenosis of aqueduct of Sylvius results in communicating hydrocephalus",
      "Hydrocephalus ex vacuo is commonly seen in infants"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "There is compensatory enlargement of the ventricles in response to loss of brain tissue In hydrocephalus ex vacuo"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "The most common haemodynamic mechanism of pulmonary oedema is",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Decrease oncotic pressure",
      "High altitude oedema",
      "Lymphatic obstruction",
      "Inflammation of the blood vessels",
      "Increase hydrostatic pressure"
    ],
    "answer": ["Increase hydrostatic pressure"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "The mediastinum in obstructive atelectasis shifts towards",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "The same side",
      "The opposite side",
      "No shift",
      "Either side depending on the cause",
      "The opposite side if it is cause by tuberculosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["The same side"],
    "explanation": "Resuptive/Obstructive: mediastium push to the affected side \ncompressive ateletasis : pushes mediastinum to opposite\nObstructive Fibrosis and the lungs colapse to the affected side",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "In bronchial asthma there is ",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Obstructive atelectasis",
      "Compressive atelectasis",
      "patchy atelectasis",
      "Lobar atelectasis",
      "Diffuse atelectasis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Obstructive atelectasis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "The main source of injury in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Platelets",
      "Macrophages",
      "Neutrophils",
      "Basophils",
      "Lymphocytes"
    ],
    "answer": ["Macrophages"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in not seen in one of those conditions",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Acute pancreatitis",
      "Drug idiosyncrasy",
      "Nephrotic syndrome",
      "Aspiration pneumonia",
      "Oxygen inhalation in excess"
    ],
    "answer": ["Oxygen inhalation in excess"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "Acute cor pulmonale can occur because of",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Aortic valve stenosis",
      "Pulmonary embolism",
      "Mitral valve stenosis",
      "Left heart failure",
      "Pulmonary hypertension"
    ],
    "answer": ["Pulmonary embolism"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "Heart failure cells are",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Degenerated cells in myocardial infarction",
      "Type II pneumocytes that produce lung surfactant",
      "Necrotic cells that are responsible for heart failure",
      "Macrophages that are laden with haemosiderin in chronic pulmonary congestion",
      "Swollen myocardial cells in heart failure"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Macrophages that are laden with haemosiderin in chronic pulmonary congestion"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Brown induration of the lung is seen in",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Chronic pulmonary congestion",
      "Pulmonary haemorrhage",
      "Pulmonary embolism",
      "Pulmonary infarction",
      "Pulmonary carcinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Chronic pulmonary congestion"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "Wedge-shape shadow on chest X ray indicates",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "ARDS",
      "Pulmonary oedema",
      "Pulmonary infarction",
      "Pneumonitis",
      "emphysema"
    ],
    "answer": ["Pulmonary infarction"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "Centrincinar emphysema usually affects",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Upper lobes of the lungs",
      "Lower of the lungs",
      "Middle lobes of the lung",
      "Lower zone of the upper lobes",
      "Lower zone of the middle lobes"
    ],
    "answer": ["Upper lobes of the lungs"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "Earliest Features of chronic bronchitis",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Goblet cells increase in small airways",
      "Hypersecretion of mucus in large airways",
      "Obstruction Of small bronchi and bronchioles",
      "Hypertrophy of bronchial smooth muscles",
      "Hyperplasia of type II pneumocytes"
    ],
    "answer": ["Hypersecretion of mucus in large airways"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "The ratio of relative thickness of mucus gland layer with the thickness of the wall between the epithelium and cartilage in the bronchi is called",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Curschmann spiral",
      "Respiratory quotient",
      "Reid index",
      "Charcot leyden index",
      "Quetlet Index"
    ],
    "answer": ["Reid index"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "The normal Reid index is",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": ["< 0.4", "> 0.4", "> 0.6", "> 0.8", "< 0.7"],
    "answer": ["< 0.4"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "One of the following is not found in bronchial asthma",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Curschmann spirals",
      "Charcot-leyden crystals",
      "Eosinophils",
      "Columnar epithelial cells",
      "Langhans type giant cells"
    ],
    "answer": ["Langhans type giant cells"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "One of the following is not a characteristic feature in the stage of red hepatization in lobar pneumonia",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Congested septal capillaries",
      "White cell exudation into the alveoli",
      "Enzymatic digestion of the alveolar exudates",
      "Alveolar spaces filled with fibrin",
      "The cut surface resembles the cut surface of liver"
    ],
    "answer": ["Enzymatic digestion of the alveolar exudates"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "Which of these is true of infective endocarditis?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Friable vegetations Libmann sacks endocarditis",
      "Staphylococcus aureus is the commonest infetive agent",
      "Streptococcus viridans affects normal heart valve",
      "Intracerebral abscess is a complication"
    ],
    "answer": ["Friable vegetations Libmann sacks endocarditis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Which Of these is not a feature of rheumatic fever?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "subcutaneous nodules",
      "Pancarditis",
      "Chorea",
      "Ashoff bodies",
      "Janeway lesions"
    ],
    "answer": ["Janeway lesions"],
    "explanation": "Janeway lesions is found in acute form of bacterial endocarditis",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Endomyocardial fibrosis is characterized by",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Dilated ventricular chambers",
      "Subaortic left ventricular stenosis",
      "Bread and butter pericarditis",
      "Subendocardial ventricular fibrosis",
      "Sub-aortic stenosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Subendocardial ventricular fibrosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "Which of these is a feature of right ventricular failure",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Hypoxic encephalopathy",
      "Acute tubular necrosis",
      "Nutmeg liver",
      "Concentric left ventricular hypertrophy",
      "Pulmonary oedema"
    ],
    "answer": ["Nutmeg liver"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Kidneys in benign hypertension are characterized by",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Deep scars on subcortical surfaces",
      "Thyroidization of tubules",
      "Finely granular subcortical surfaces",
      "Coarsely granular subcortical surfaces",
      "Polycystic kidneys"
    ],
    "answer": ["Finely granular subcortical surfaces"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "What is the best description of Eisenmenger's syndrome?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "It occurs when a right to left shunt becomes left to right due to build-up of pressure in the left side of the heart",
      "It results from failure of the aorticopulmonary septum to spiral",
      "A component of tetralogy of Fallot",
      "An initial left to right shunt becomes right to left due to increased pulmonary blood flow and eventual right ventricular hypertrophy",
      "Claudication resulting from coarctation of the aorta"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "An initial left to right shunt becomes right to left due to increased pulmonary blood flow and eventual right ventricular hypertrophy"
    ],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Dilated cardiomyopathy is characterised by",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Thickened inner third of ventricular wall",
      "Asymmetrical septal hypertrophy",
      "Reduction in the left ventricular cavity",
      "Amyloid deposits in ventricles",
      "Systolic dysfunction"
    ],
    "answer": ["Systolic dysfunction"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "What is the most frequent aetiologic agent of infective endocarditis in intravenous drug users?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Streptococcus viridans",
      "Streptococcus bovis",
      "Staphylococcus aureus",
      "Staphylococcus epidermidis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Staphylococcus aureus"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "Which of the following artery is most likely involved in myocardial infaction",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Right coronary artery",
      "Left anterior descending artery",
      "Left circumflex artery",
      "Posterior descending artery",
      "Common carotid artery"
    ],
    "answer": ["Left anterior descending artery"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "Which of these is a left to right shunt?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Persistent truncus arteriosus",
      "Tetralogy of Fallot",
      "Transposition of great arteries",
      "Tricuspid atresia",
      "Ventricular septal defect"
    ],
    "answer": ["Ventricular septal defect"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "Which of these is a feature of malignant hypentension",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Flea-bitten kidneys",
      "Fine granularity of renal cortical surfaces",
      "Hyaline arteriolosclerosis",
      "Blood pressure of 180/100mmHg",
      "Left ventricular wall thickness of 1.4cm"
    ],
    "answer": ["Flea-bitten kidneys"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "Which of these is not a risk factor for atherosclerosis?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Male gender",
      "Smoking",
      "Premenopause",
      "Hypertension",
      "Diabetes mellitus"
    ],
    "answer": ["Premenopause"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Which of these is not a compensatory mechanism in congestive cardiac failure?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "protein synthesis",
      "Bradycardia",
      "Activation Of the renin-angiotensin system",
      "Increased levels of cathecolamines",
      "Left ventricular hypertrophy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Bradycardia"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "With regard to rheumatic heart disease",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Mitral stenosis is common complication",
      "Vegetations are usually laden with bacteria",
      "Staphylococcal pharyngitis or Sepsis may precede the diseae",
      "The aortic valve is so commonly affected",
      "Aschoff nodules are present only in the endocardium"
    ],
    "answer": ["Mitral stenosis is common complication"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a complication of atherosclerosis",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Thrombus formation",
      "Aortic aneurysm",
      "Myocardial infarction",
      "Pulmonary oedema",
      "Hypertension"
    ],
    "answer": ["Pulmonary oedema"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Which forensic pathologist system is used in Nigeria?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Procurator fiscal system",
      "Medical examiner system",
      "Chief medical examiner",
      "Coroner's system"
    ],
    "answer": ["Coroner's system"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "The following are with fresh water drowning except",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Massive pulmonary oedema and haemoconcentration",
      "Haemdilution",
      "Acute myocardial failure",
      "Hyperkalemia",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Massive pulmonary oedema and haemoconcentration"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "A dead body was observed to be in sustained contraction, guesstimate the time since death",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "12-24 hours after death",
      "0-14 hours after death",
      "6-14 hours after death",
      "12-36 hours after death",
      "36 hours after death"
    ],
    "answer": ["6-14 hours after death"],
    "explanation": "Contraction starts after 6hr peak for 6hr  sustained for 12hr  and comes down for 6hr",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "Kayser-Fleischer ring is pathognomonic of which of these disease conditions",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Haemochromatosis",
      "Wilson's disease",
      "Familial Adenomatous Polyposis",
      "Hypertensive retinopathy",
      "Diabetic retinopathy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Wilson's disease"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Vitamin A storing cells are central to the pathogenesis of which of the following?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Vitamin A deficiency",
      "Deficiency of fat soluble vitamins",
      "Haemochromatosis",
      "Liver cirrhosis",
      "Hepatocellular carcinoma"
    ],
    "answer": ["Liver cirrhosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Which of the following is true with Yregards to cirrhosis",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "It may be caused by hepatitis A virus",
      "It may be caused by hepatitis B virus",
      "The cause may be cryptogenic in about 15% of cases",
      "Alcohol play an insignificant role in western world",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["It may be caused by hepatitis B virus"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "Bronze skin is associated with which of the following disorder",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Liver cirrhosis",
      "Inborn error of copper accumulation disease",
      "Haemochromatosis",
      "Wilson's disease",
      "Alpha 1 antitrpsin deficiency"
    ],
    "answer": ["Haemochromatosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "Liver cirrhosis is characterized by the following features except",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "End stage chronic liver disease",
      "Distruption of liver architecture",
      "Nodules of regenerating hepatocytes",
      "Zone 3 necrosis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Zone 3 necrosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "A cigarette smoker presented with panacinar emphysema and micronodular cirrhosis. What is the most likely aetiological factor?",
    "questionType": "objective",
    "options": [
      "Alcohol",
      "Viral hepatitis",
      "Primary hemochromatosis",
      "Wilson disease",
      "Alpha I antitrypsin deficiency"
    ],
    "answer": ["Alpha I antitrypsin deficiency"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": "Morbid",
    "topics": [],
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionScore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "isCompleted": false,
    "averageRating": 0,
    "variationGiven": 0,
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": "MORBID ANATOMY",
    "course": "PATHOLOGY"
  }
]
